1 16 of a Sam's Club Apple Pie has
370 calories in it which in layman terms
is a small piece of pie for a boatload
of calories this is
in fact most holiday treats have an
enormous amount of fat sugar and
calories so I wanted to take some of the
most famous desserts and turn them into
a protein packed ice cream you could
enjoy any time of year let's
get into it Oberweis eggnog is the best
eggnog in existence but one I can't get
it in Texas and two it is 240 calories
for just four ounces or a half a cup
let's flip the script put a pint on a
scale and add 290 grams of one percent
Fair life milk if you can't find one
percent Fair life I suggest buying a
half gallon of both fat free and 2
percent and adding 145 grams of both
this milk has double the protein of
regular milk but if you don't care about
the extra protein and want something a
little bit cheaper you can add regular
old one percent milk as well then add
120 grams Almond Breeze eggnog and 4.2
grams vanilla extract I tested multiple
eggnogs from different brands and for
the calories and flavor combination I
don't think you can beat the Almond
Breeze eggnog if you have another you
prefer feel free to use it just make
sure you account for the calories for
the last of the wet ingredients we will
separate an egg white from the yolk and
add the yolk to the ice cream whoa Nick
why are we using an egg yolk an egg yolk
is very commonly used as an emulsifier
for ice cream simply put an emulsifier
helps the ice cream have a better mouth
feel and texture while eating it in
addition egg yolks also slow down the
melting process of the ice cream so you
can enjoy it for longer I went over
using raw eggs extensively in my cookie
dough video I posted last week which you
can check out after this video but if
you don't feel comfortable using an egg
yolk in your ice cream feel free to sub
in an extra 20 grams of one percent milk
now place a medium sized Bowl on a scale
and add 20 grams Gourmet vanilla PE
science protein powder 40 grams
granulated swerve 1 gram cinnamon 1 gram
salt 1 gram xanthan gum and a dash of
nutmeg a protein powder that is a whey
casein blend is preferred for this
recipe and PE science is top quality if
anyone watching uses a different brand
for these recipes please let the people
know your results in the comments
section below so people have more
options it is greatly appreciated you
can also use code e4cm to get 10 off any
PE science order which helps support the
channel as well now take a whisk and
blend all of your dry ingredients
together this is going to help prevent
clumping then grab a small hand mixer
like this and start mixing while slowly
pouring in your dry ingredients it
usually takes me about 30 to 45 seconds
to get all of the ingredients mixed in
once they are mixed in keep blending for
an additional 90 seconds this will help
to make sure everything is dissolved as
best as possible put a lid on your pint
throw it in the freezer and it is time
to wait 24 hours I highly suggest making
two or three at a time so that you are
stacked up throughout the week and never
have to wait again you can purchase
extra pints through Amazon or directly
through ninja and they are well worth it
in my opinion I have an eggnog cream
ready to go so let's get it out of the
freezer start a timer for one minute and
run it under hot water this will help
the edges loosen up making less ice
crystals on the outside of the Pint now
wipe off the Pint pop the top off and
load it into the creamy hit the the ice
cream function and let it do its thing
once finished I don't even look at it
and load it right back in for a respin
when the respin is completed it looks
crumbly on top like this it is good to
eat at this point but I like it even
more when adding in a mix-in spin even
without having any mix-ins I feel as
though the Final Mix and setting gives
me a true pint consistency that is
similar to leaving the pine out for 15
minutes before eating it load it back up
one more time and hit that mixing
setting you now have an ultra smooth
delectably creamy eggnog flavored ice
cream that comes in at a fraction of the
calories of anything you can get at the
store as a staple at any Thanksgiving
dessert table and apple pie ice cream
recipe was a must get a pint on a scale
and add 410 grams one percent Fair life
milk 4.2 grams vanilla extract and an
egg yolk the extra egg whites always get
put into a container and usually get
used in an omelette during breakfast the
next day again if you don't want to use
the egg yolk add an extra 20 grams of
milk instead put the Pint off to the
side get a medium sized Bowl on a scale
and add 20 grams PE science
Snickerdoodle protein powder 40 gram
swerve 1 gram apple pie spice 1 gram
salt and 1 gram of xanthan gum xanthan
gum is an important ingredient that
helps prevent the formation of ice
crystals in the ice cream and makes for
a richer smoother and creamier final
product it is also dirt cheap and will
last you forever I will put anything I
use in the description below take a
whisk and blend the dry ingredients
thoroughly and like this video if you
like recipes like this using the same
blender you used in the last recipe
start mixing in the dry ingredients over
a 30 to 45 second period I like to make
sure all of the ingredients are
dissolved before I keep pouring in more
ingredients similar to whisking the
ingredients together beforehand this
will prevent clumping after the dry
ingredients are poured in keep mixing
for an additional 90 seconds once
finished pop the top on and throw it in
the freezer for 24 hours hours per usual
I already have one ready in the freezer
so let's take it rinse it under hot
water for 60 seconds and pop it in the
creamy mix it on the ice cream setting
and while that is going let's get our
mixings ready first we have apple pie
Toast Crunch this stuff is absolutely
amazing on its own but will provide
incredible flavor and texture to the ice
cream as well put a small bowl on the
scale and add 12 grams to it second we
need an apple the fresh Apple brings
another sharp contrast of flavor and
texture that complements the ice cream
and will make what I think is my best
ice cream yet take a peeler and peel
about one third of the Apple cut off the
part without the skin which should be
about 20 grams slice into small slivers
about an eighth of an inch apart turn
the Apple 90 degrees and repeat these
are perfect bite-sized pieces that will
spread evenly throughout the ice cream
lastly we will add a pinch of swerve
along with a dash of cinnamon and mix
everything together again this brings
deeper complexity to both the mix-ins
and overall dish which just brings it up
another notch if the first mix finishes
while you are cutting the apples feel
free to load it back up and re-spin it
this should give you enough time to get
the mixins finished if you haven't got
them done already once completed grab a
knife and scoop out the middle of the
ice cream I like to get about a one inch
circle cleared out to make room for the
mix-ins I will then add a third of the
pieces of Apple followed by a third of
the cereal and repeat until I have just
a little bit left for topping the pine I
then take the ice cream I initially
scooped out put it on top of the mix-ins
and create an even layer on top you can
use a rubber spatula for this but I just
use my fingers because it's easier now
load it back up and hit the mixing
setting once finished you can top the
Pint with the mixins you have left or my
favorite is to grab an ice cream scoop
and get two to three scoops into a
waffle cone and sprinkle the extras on
the Scoops themselves either way you do
it this ice cream will be at the top of
your favorites list for many weeks or
even months to come no matter which
flavor you choose you can't go wrong
they are both loaded with flavor packed
with protein and are good any time of
year there may be times you need
something a little bit lower on the
calories and it is good to have options
ready to go in the freezer to make it a
moment's notice these ice creams have
nearly half the calories of Halo top and
have just as much if not more flavor if
you make any of these recipes please tag
me on Instagram because I love to see
the Recreations and leave a comment so
people know if it is worth making or not
until next time deuces